Carrie and Diane, what's the main advice that you would give to
Carrie Diane 在设计实验方面
analysts as they're designing their experiments?
你们有什么建议要分享给分析师的？
>> I don't mean to sound trite, but just do it.
我并不想说些陈词滥调 但现在我想说的是 放手做吧
Right? The work that you're going to do in
你做的所有工作 包括选择分组单元
choosing your diversion, in terms of setting what you need to be consistent?
例如设置需要保持一致的事物
Or choosing your population to say who's actually going to be affected?
选择总体 例如哪些用户将实际受到影响
Or the sizing.
或者确定规模
All of that work is going to ensure that the work that you do in actually running
都将确保实验能够顺利运行
the experiment, not to mention the work that you're putting your users through
更不用说你针对让用户实际看到更改
of actually seeing how they're going to react to those changes,
并了解他们的反应所以做的工作
all of that isn't wasted.
这些工作都会有所回报
So, really, just go through the work of designing your experiment properly.
所以 大家尽管放手设计实验吧
>> Yeah, like we talked about in lesson three,
是的 就像我们在第三课中提到的
even if your analytic calculations don't turn out to be exactly right,
即便分析计算结果不是很准确
they really give you a good framework for starting to understand how
它们也能为你提供一个良好的框架
many users you're going to need, what f, type of variability you're looking at,
以便你开始理解你需要多少用户 你要关注哪些类型的差异性
whether what you're looking at is even realistic for your user population.
你关注的内容就你的用户总体而言是否现实
And that's a great starting point, and
这是一个很好的起点
it forces you to think through a lot of these issues.
它会迫使你思考许多其他问题
>> Okay, and is there anything in particular you'd like to call out?
好的 有什么需要特别注意的事项？
>> So, what I'd call out is really the interaction between your choice of
我想强调一下指标和分组单元之间的相互作用
metrics, that we discussed in lesson three, with your unit of diversion.
我们曾在第三课中讨论过这个问题
Some of your metrics may not be valid to compute given your unit of diversion.
在使用特定分组单元时 某些指标是无法计算的
And th-, and what can also happen is that the variability of your metric can
另外 指标的差异性可能根据
really change depending on what you choose as your unit of diversion.
所选择的分组单元发生重大变化
The other thing to keep in mind is the, is always going to be an iterative
另一点需要注意的是 始终使用迭代过程
process, even if, or especially if, you're setting up a series of
特别是你要设置一系列实验
experiments or you want to set this up for your company in general.
或者要针对公司整体开展一个实验时
You're going to go through the process of trying to figure out what
你可能要经历这么一个过程
metrics will work for
确定适合使用哪个指标
you, run a few experiments, see if you like the results.
运行几次实验 查看结果是否令人满意
You know, can you really see something?
看看能否得出一些见解
And you may have to go back through this process and
然后你可能需要重复这一过程
really settle in something that works for you in terms of your business.
以便确定哪些事物适合你的公司
>> Now, we've talked a lot about building intuition, and
我们已就培养直觉进行大量讨论
what I would say is that the entire point of building the intuition is that
我要说的是 培养直觉就是
as you're going through this iterative process, you're
在迭代过程中
able to use your intuition to better make guesses about what's going to work.
你能够使用直觉更准确地猜测哪些事物可能有用
So you basically speed up this process.
从而加快过程速度
>> That makes sense.
有道理
And is there anything else?
还有别的吗？
>> So the last thing that I try to point out is that
我最后指出一点
your choice of unit of diversion and your choice of population makes for
分组单元和总体的选择
really good choices about your invariant choice.
在一定程度上决定了不变量的选择
We talked about those a little bit in lesson three where
我们曾在第三课中提及这个问题
you have these metrics that you use as invariance, or basically sanity checks,
你使用一些不变的指标 或者完整性检查
to make sure that your experiment and your control are run properly.
来确保实验组和对照组顺利运行
Well, if you choose a unit of diversion of cookie and
如果选择 cookie 作为分组单元
a population of English, then what you can do is saying, well, I'm going to
并使用英语用户作为总体 那么你可以
count how many cookies are in English for both my experiment and my control.
计算实验组和对照组中英语用户产生的 cookie 数量
And if those are the same,
如果计数相同
then I have some idea that my experiment has actually been run properly.
那么我会知道实验进行得很顺利
>> And this is a really great time to keep an eye out for surprises.
这时候需要留意意外事件
One of the most common things we see is people design a feature
举例而言 在设计功能时 人们通常会认为
thinking it will only trigger, you know, 5% of the time on their site.
这个功能在网站中只有 5% 的触发机率
And then when they do their first day of an experiment they find
然而在实验的第一天
that the feature is on 80% of all their traffic.
他们发现有 80% 的流量都使用了这个功能
And it's okay to get surprises, but
发生意外事件也没有关系
do keep your eye on the data as it starts to come in,
但你要留意所产生的数据
because that's a great time to figure out that something's gone wrong.
你通常会在这时候发现某些问题